We are ready to clean the supply
items for our ampule based
preparation.
We'll get the outer wrapping of
our IV piggyback, and when you
are bringing syringes and
needles and the Isopropyl
alcohol prep swabs in, you'll
want to separate all of those
because there's a lot of
particulate when you pull those
apart and you'll clean each of
those items off and put them
into your supply bin.
Notice that the patient CSP
label is in a plastic bag.
You'll want to wipe off that
plastic bag before it comes into
the buffer room.
We do take calculators into the
clean room.
They must be able to withstand
all of the cleaning items.
Use a hard plastic and a hard
plastic for the numbers and
function buttons.
You do want to do all the
calculations before you come
into the buffer room so that you
know that you have all of the
supply items that you need.
The compounder is now prepared
to do the hand hygiene and
garbing procedure.
Welcome to the small volume
ampule based preparation.
The direct compounding area has
all of the supplies we will use
in this ampule manipulation.
Normal saline, IV piggyback, 100
milliliters, promethazine, 25
milligram per mill ampule, 70%
sterile IPA swabs, A syringe, a
regular needle and A5 Micron
filter needle.
Open the outer packaging of our
four piggyback and we'll open a
sterile IPA swab and place that
on the work surface.
We'll open another sterile IPA
swab and we'll clean the
injection port of the bag.
We'll clear the head of our
ampule, and then we'll open a
sterile IPA pad for our needle
cap and another sterile IPA swab
so that we can clean the neck of
our ampule.
With one hand, we'll hold the
ampule, the body of the ampule.
With one hand, the opposite
hand, we'll use our thumb and
our forefinger.
We'll apply pressure on the
neck.
You want to point away from the
HEPA filter toward the side
panel of the PEC and then put
that back on the DCA.
We will open the outer packaging
of our syringe.
We'll open the outer packaging
of our needle.
We'll attach our needle to our
syringe.
We'll activate that plunger to
loosen it.
We'll get into a dart, take our
cap off, put it on that IPA pad
you can lift your ampule.
Put the needle and syringe in
hold on to the barrel and the
index finger.
You can pull on the flat knob
the volume of your dose and then
what would be in your hub and
lumen.
We will recap and now we're
going to troubleshoot that air
bubble.
We're going to pull back our
plunger.
We're going to tap, tap our
barrel.
When you tap tap, you must pull
back and then we're going to
trap the liquid in the hub of
our needle.
We're going to get into a dart,
take our cap off.
We need to go back into our
ampule so that we now will go
down to our exact dose for our
patient.
Once we confirm that volume,
we'll recap tap slide snap.
Now we are going to change
needles.
We need what is in our hub and
lumen, so pull back on your
plunger when changing needles,
needles first, we're going to
bring our five Micron filter
needle out of the packaging.
Be careful of the critical site
and now we're going to change
needles.
We're going to take the cap off
of our filter needle, we're
going to pick up our IV
piggyback and you want to go
straight into the port.
You can push the liquid in
by that flat knob
Come out by the barrel and then
we'll pick up the IV
piggyback.
We'll mix it and we'll check to
make sure that there's no
particulates.